- Guys, thank you very much for being here.
Very, very, very excited to be here with you all
on this at this event to really talk about, obviously,
and very exciting development we have.
Really not only with FDUSD,
but really on the future of money as well.
I know how busy everybody is,
so thank you for making time
so we can share our passion of the topic
which you guys all, this episode is powered by Zappobank.
Experience the future of banking with Zappobank,
the first fully licensed
and regulated Bitcoin enabled banking group.
With Zappobank's all in one app,
you can grow, transact, and secure your Bitcoin.
Earn annual Bitcoin yield paid daily
on your Bitcoin and US dollar savings
plus cashback on your card spending.
Or instantly send and receive Bitcoin
with the Lightning Network
and seamlessly transact in USDC, USDT, US dollars,
euros, and pounds.
All this is backed by rock solid security,
including military-grade Swiss bunkers,
cutting edge digital protocols,
and strict regulatory oversight.
Sign up now at zappobank.com/capsule
or check the link in the episode description.
- I'm very, very excited to be joined by Vincent Chock today,
who's not only the CEO co-founder of First Digital,
but fun fact about him,
he owns a stake in a Napa Winery
where they made the board-ape wines.
I have it in my office, a very good one.
That was a great contribution to the ecosystem.
Vincent, great to have you with us today.
Guys, we're gonna have a lot of fun,
a lot of developments, and at the end,
we have even a surprise announcement as well.
I'm excited to share with you all today.
So Vincent, I've known you for almost a decade now.
Many people know you as a CEO of First Digital,
but can you share maybe from all the things
you guys could look at, why stablecoins?
And then we'll delve into it.
- Well, I mean, I think,
hi, everyone, Vincent Chock here.
Thanks for coming.
Appreciate the organizers for setting up
the stablecoin summit.
I almost said stablecoin summer, actually,
but why stablecoin?
- Not as well, but that's a different story.
- I think stablecoin is really important
to the growth of the digital asset industry.
There's a lot of initiatives for really getting
to a Web3 world, which I think we're still
quite far away from.
As earlier, Paul had mentioned that stablecoin
in the next decade will hit over $2 trillion.
And at the moment, we're, what, $170 million?
So there's a lot more to grow.
So we think that we're in the right position right now.
Yes, there's a lot of mention of two giants.
However, I think this world needs optionality,
or else everyone's going to be driving a Tesla.
- So actually, on the topic, you mentioned the two giants,
and I get it, the analogy with Tesla.
When people ask you, how do you practically
if you're as different from some of the other giants
and others, by the way, you've seen a market,
like what do you guys say there?
- Well, I think, of course, we're one-to-one
back US dollar stablecoin.
But how we're different, I think, is sort of our DNA.
We're structured as trusts.
So we understand rules and regulations.
If there are regulations coming in,
and a lot of talks about regulations
in the future about licensing.
However, who will be the actual stablecoin out there
that can integrate and absorb new regulation
when it does come in?
And I think that's our position.
We're strong that way.
A lot of people don't know, as a trust company,
we have to understand all aspects.
Tax reporting.
Regulation in the facts of what is our reporting obligation
on AML KYC compliance.
And that's something that our stablecoin
was built on top of, instead of just tech.
And I think going forward, the way that we look at ourselves,
and they mentioned over 100 stablecoins in the market
today, which is fine for us.
I think the competition is healthy, but to us,
everybody has a role.
For the two giants and us, we're a very young stablecoin,
less than a year and a half old.
We've grown great partnerships.
But we look at ourselves and some of the major stablecoins
as sort of intermediary banks to other stablecoins being built.
So a lot of banks today doesn't have direct US rail,
so they rely on intermediary banks.
So we can play that role.
We can help people build on top of our stablecoins,
other currencies.
So I want to talk about that, especially
I know you're a big fan of neo-banking as well.
I'm going to talk about that in a second.
But if you had a message to policymakers today--
actually, on my show on CNBC, I had the Paolo DeSjio Tada
recently, and ask them the same question where we have often
the banks are a weak point of the entire system.
We saw, for example, USTC was on stage before.
When SVB went down, actually, there was a serious deep peg.
Ironically, the risky part of the US, the stablecoin,
was actually the banking system, right?
If you had a message to policymakers in the room,
and you mentioned regulations, what would that message be?
What do you think would be the way to designing it?
Is it a trust?
Or is it something else you would be using?
The regulators, the US stablecoin bill
guidelines that came out in consultation paper,
does actually state our structure as a deposit-taking
institution, we're a qualified custodian,
to keep the separation of assets.
And we do that.
So we have dual balance sheet.
I think it's important that we use the strongest financial
institution as our treasury.
And by keeping a dual balance sheet,
it means that there's a clear separation of liabilities.
When we use our own money, if, for example,
any companies decide, let's take action on first digital,
for any reason, they can't touch our client
asset because it's very segregated.
Unlike most stablecoins, they don't understand
how to keep those assets separated,
whereby, if there is any future actions against the company,
the customer assets are safely kept.
It's very interesting.
You know, even as a lawyer, when I look at it,
the trust structure has so many benefits, right?
And I wish there was more awareness
of the benefits of trust structures,
actually, including for stablecoins.
And the broader community as well, by the way,
on many regards.
One thing as well, on the topic of regulations,
you guys obviously based in Hong Kong, right?
Big presence in Hong Kong and in Asia as well.
And I know you guys are obviously
looking around the world as well.
What do you see as the, from a regulatory perspective,
do you see a particular opportunity in Asia?
For example, in Hong Kong or other places?
Yeah, I think so. I think the position of being regulated,
a lot of companies think that just getting being licensed
means that they really understand how to operate
and do what's for the best interest of the clients
and for the industry.
But really, truly understanding what regulation is
doesn't mean that I can just operate freely
with a license hanging on my back.
But understanding, all right, our responsibilities.
How do we deal with compliance?
How do we deal with internal controls?
Right now, there's a lot of talk about doing that cybersecurity.
There's so much focus on cybersecurity,
but really has anybody really dug into the company's
back-end regulation internal control policies, AML policies.
So this is the focus of where we are going.
Very, very interesting.
And actually, regionally, as well, Vincent,
when, obviously, we talk about the role of stablecoins.
First of all, it's maybe a rhetorical question,
but do you believe that stablecoins could be the killer app
for the digital asset space?
Well, seven years ago, I was listening to someone's TED Talk,
my friend here, which huge fan.
And you did mention, at that time, seven years ago,
banking today is going to be different from banking
in the future.
And stablecoin for fintech--
his talk was about fintech, and really innovative talk.
But today, stablecoin is fuel.
It provides-- it's like a steroid for fintech.
Without a stablecoin, there is no liquidity.
So I've said this.
It's oxygen for exchanges.
It's oxygen for OTCs.
It's oxygen for a lot of the builders out there, chains.
If there's no liquidity, then there
is really no growth in the whole crypto market.
Interesting.
And then when you're looking at the--
obviously-- and I'm sure it's a question many people
have in the room, right?
When we think FTUSD, there's been, obviously,
a lot of collaborations you guys announced.
One of them is actually with Binance.
Can you be clarified for the audience and for us?
Like, what is that relationship?
What is the collaboration?
What are you guys seeing there?
And how do you think that helped, actually,
the rise of the growth of FTUSD?
Well, partnership is really a key to any growth.
I mean, like I said, we don't want one company
to monopolize the whole industry.
So there has to be choices out there.
And I think Binance is free to have partnership
with any stablecoin out there.
And there's no exclusivity between them and us.
But we know that there is other stablecoins listed on Binance.
But we want to be the best.
We want to provide new, different types of utilities
for how do we expand to different parts of the industry,
providing real-world assets, again,
talking about being a correspondent sort of bank
for other stablecoins to build on top.
And having Binance as a platform really also
helps the smaller platform connect and grow
as a whole in the whole industry.
So we're really relatively small at this point in time,
not FTUSD.
But fun fact is we try to take whatever wins we can.
But a lot of talks about Tether, a lot of talk about Circle.
But a lot of people don't know that velocity-wise,
we are 10 times more than Circle, velocity-wise.
We have four times larger than Tether, if you do the math.
We have been in existence for about a year and a half,
just under a year and a half.
We're at about almost $3 billion.
Our top line was up to $4.3 billion last, I think, May or March.
We were the fastest growing stablecoin to hit a billion
at less than eight months.
We hit $2 billion in about 12 months.
So if we look at those facts, I think
that just is a testament to the industry looking
for other alternative stablecoins,
that it's not going to be all the apples and apples, right?
I'm happy you mentioned this, actually.
One complaint I have on the broader stablecoin ecosystem
is we often talk about assets and stablecoin.
But we don't talk about velocity or volumes, which I think
are equally important in many regards.
Do you know what's driving a lot of this velocity you mentioned?
Is it the launch pad on by that, is it?
Yeah, I mean, there's launch pad.
I mean, that's one major reason.
And Devere mentioned that earlier.
Also, I think that we're trying to really
grow with different chains.
And getting into different markets,
when we talk about payments, that's really
on my priority list to focus on cross-border.
That's an interesting answer.
Vincent, I want to talk about the topic
I know is very close to your heart.
And I think the topic of the future money as well.
You know, when we talk about the future of banking, right?
I mean, obviously, we all have issues now
with correspondent banks and generals.
Probably, I would say, it's one of the weakest points
we have in the crypto ecosystem right now.
When we talk about neo-banking, really
where we talk about a banking role that is built on DeFi,
on smart contracts, I know you've
been a big advocate of that.
How do you imagine a future of banking
on a neo-free banking model?
If you think it'll happen as well.
Well, yeah, I mean, financial inclusion,
we've talked about this for many years.
How do we help the unbanked or the less-banked?
I mean, you mentioned this about developed countries,
not only undeveloped countries with the unbanked,
but developed countries like the US, one in four households,
doesn't have bank accounts.
I think stablecoin will eliminate and provide a banking
infrastructure, at least somebody,
doesn't matter how much they make, now has the ability
to actually start in creating a financial footprint,
regardless of making hundreds of thousands a year,
or just a few thousand dollars a year.
But this can give everyone the opportunity
to really start being a part of the global financial infrastructure,
regardless of your status, regardless of your nationality.
So neo-banking, yes, neo-banking still
will require proper regulation, but this
is where DeFi comes in, where I think there's builders,
I think there's infrastructure providers like ourselves,
that needs to have the moral responsibility
to be our own regulators and not only rely on governments telling us
what to do, especially in an industry where the government
themselves are still discovering how to regulate.
Also, I would argue that if you come in regulations,
I mean, the code is there.
I mean, literally, the regulations are there.
In a way, also, there's no fractional banking in a model like that,
or interior, you could not have it,
which becomes very interesting.
But how do you think that will interact, though, if I'm today,
I'm the Fed, I'm a central bank, and I'm regulating the banking system.
This is how money is being created by the banking system
when they're lending out, because neo-banking right now
could exist in parallel, in the same way we have stable coins
that exist in interior outside of the payment system, right?
How do you think the central banks will react to the rise of neo-banking,
which is very small right now.
I mean, DeFi is, I don't know whether our TVL is right now, right?
But I mean, it's still relatively small.
How do you think that interaction will go?
I think they're forced to really look
at that this is something that's going to be inevitable,
especially when we see the growth of the FinTech industry.
And there's a comment saying, if 100% of zero is still zero,
so with neo-banking, you have now the global reach,
where we have access to 7 billion people
instead of only 700 million.
You know what I mean?
So it's just the scalability of using neo-banking will create--
so central bank will have to look at that.
In another ways, as well, as if you think about the poverty line.
A lot of governments, a lot of heritage funds,
a lot of pensions are actually broke,
because they have to take care of the pensions.
But now, if you allow people to create their own small pension,
that will relieve the pressure of governments.
Right.
I'm glad you enabled them to actually leverage it as well.
I think it's going to be very interesting,
because if you think how the crypto industry evolved,
the last couple of years where securities regulators came in,
and we have all the even-- the last couple of days,
we had so many issues with the SEC and others, right?
It's going to be, I think, very interesting
how this dynamic will evolve, and I agree with you.
I think the fact that what you're mentioning,
that it's really going to enable a lot of people
to access the system, it has a big role.
What do you see, then, stablecoins?
What role do you see stablecoins play in your banking model?
Do they become the de facto payment rails
that everybody is using?
I think it's definitely for settlements.
I think it's an important element to the growth of a lot
of what we're building today on different protocols.
One day, I've said it before, every major protocol
will have its own native stablecoin.
And to support that, there is going
to be traditional infrastructure that needs to be in place.
People want to provide stablecoin with yields.
In some cases, that's a security, right?
But if you have-- everybody has their role
and responsibility dealing with the banking side,
holding the asset, segregating the asset properly,
making proper reporting, making sure
that money is not in the wrong hands
and being used in the wrong way, right?
Everybody has to be specialized in what they're doing.
So this is how I think stablecoin really
plays into the whole ecosystem in the sense
that for us to service the RWA world,
we're hearing a lot about that.
I think it's not only the stablecoin
and the summer is also the RWA summer now.
Everybody's talking about how do we tokenize RWA's.
But earlier, Paul said there's, what, $800 trillion
of assets globally, and there's $170 billion of stablecoin.
You tell me, RWA's are tokenized assets,
and for people to actually settle on tokenized assets,
you need a stablecoin.
Have you been surprised of the growth of RWA,
especially stuff like we're seeing treasuries now
and with BlackRock I said $2 billion now?
I mean, RWA's been around for a long time.
If you look at, for example, what do you got?
Fractionalized ownership in real estate.
Back then, before blockchain, people
are just taking one title and literally drawing lines
on you on this piece, you on this piece.
But what blockchain did was now I can actually sell off
my piece without having everyone to agree.
And then it evolved into STOs, which is the traditional--
that's how we deem RWA's back then,
our stablecoin, I mean, securitized tokens.
But now RWA's is just a rebranding of the same thing.
So, yeah, I mean, it's going to be evolving as we know it.
And people are now going to be a lot more innovative
and more, I think, open to looking at how do we tokenize
everything?
I've tokenized-- as a trust company,
we've tokenized art pieces.
So we held any war halls.
We've tokenized staff, safe private equities.
But it's just opening up.
There's a lot of traditional industries
now are starting to explore how the blockchain, how
tokenizing their assets, how we can do settlements,
for example, letters of credits.
We've seen banks really stop transactions from two clients
that have agreed to doing a transaction.
But the bank says, well, I don't think I like that,
because it's the country that you're shipping from
has a lot of different-- they're not ESG compliant.
So the banks are playing this king.
Policing.
Yeah, the policing.
And it's the same thing.
I think regulators need this--
there's an important aspect to regulating
where you're either policing your members
or you're actually assisting them and educating them
how to operate around something that's
going to be inevitable.
You mentioned, I think, the letter of credits.
I'm amazed how much the LC role has not evolved.
But also, I think people underestimate,
in a non-crypto world, how much international transactions
take place on stablecoins right now.
As the business role that banks are realizing gradually,
I think there's a lot of activity.
Being based in Dubai, I just see it between Africa and Asia.
It's absolutely incredible.
You mentioned something about education.
I know this is a special day, because I was mentioning
we have a lot of surprise.
Today, we're launching the--
in partnership with actually First Digital,
World's First Interactive Crypto Book for Kids, actually.
So it's coming out today.
We'll do actually book signing later on in the lunch area.
But I know this was actually a big thing.
You know, it's called Henry and Holler.
There's a character.
It's a solidity is in there.
There's Nakamoto.
I know it's a question a lot of people get.
My daughter thinks, when people ask my kids what I do in life,
my daughter says, my dad works for Bitcoin.
So we said we have to fix this.
And actually, hopefully, it's a comic book with kids.
You guys will all get a copy, compliments of really FDUSD today.
So Vincent, really, thank you very much for supporting.
But what you think educational crypto is quite important as well.
You mentioned educating the banks.
But what about the general population on it?
And the kids, especially--
Well, of course, my kids are a little grown up now.
But your kids are quite young.
And I don't think they've ever been inside of an actual bank,
have they?
Exactly.
If we never.
So what we have to educate them on exactly the value of money,
and which is kind of lost, but the value of money
means how do you actually grow it, keep it,
and understand that there's a lot of scams in this world.
But how do we educate them to identify that?
So we have to educate using whatever medium we can.
However, unfortunately, the biggest university
in the world is YouTube right now, or Instagram,
which anybody could be a professor.
But we have to let them know what's actual real and what
to do.
It's a big challenge, actually.
Unfortunately, a lot of people are also in crypto.
Their first interaction is often a scam,
or something like that, a pump and dump,
and a pig butchering, and stuff like that, which is quite sad.
But Vincent, we have a little bit of a couple minutes left.
I hear my best friend, the bell, is here with me.
So I want to do a couple of far-round questions.
And I need one or two more answers.
And the bell is here.
I hope you guys are ready.
We're going to rock and roll with this.
So Vincent, you're in Singapore this week.
What's your favorite thing about Singapore?
My favorite thing about Singapore.
I think the Hawker food, Hawker centers.
I love it.
I had dinner there last night.
You're based in Hong Kong.
The one thing about Hong Kong, people get wrong.
That we're owned by China.
Oh boy.
So Vincent, if you're not in the crypto industry,
what would you be doing?
I think I'd be growing grapes for my winery.
That's definitely a different pace than crypto, that's for sure.
What is the one biggest risk we're facing as a crypto ecosystem
right now?
Regulation that is based by us regulation.
Yeah.
Good point.
This is a tricky one.
If you could hold one coin for the next 10 years,
you're not allowed to hold-- not after USD.
One coin you have to hold for the next 10 years
without selling, what would that be?
I like sweet.
I was not expecting.
That's interesting.
Interesting.
I'm sure there'll be a lot of conversation over lunch on that.
I'm curious why, actually, but hey, we'll talk about that
in a second.
If you could go back to school today,
or any students in the room, what
is the one course you recommend students should take
that you wish you had taken?
Drama class.
German.
Drama?
Drama, OK.
Again, very useful in crypto.
That's for sure.
Another one, interesting.
What's the best piece of advice you've ever received?
Keep things simple.
Wow.
Very good point, actually.
Very good point.
Go through the stablecoin mantra as well.
Another interesting one, Vincent.
If you can go back in history to live in any period,
any period back in history, which period would you want to live in?
When Satoshi came out with the white paper?
[LAUGHTER]
The Halloween day, 2008, here we go.
Another one, talking about the potential Satoshi,
Elon Musk gives you a call and says,
Vincent, what is the one suggestion
you have to make X or Twitter better?
What do you tell him?
Get off X.
[LAUGHTER]
Another one.
The new US president, whoever he or she may be in November,
gives you a call and makes you a crypto advisor.
What is-- and asks you for the first thing you do.
What is the first thing you would do as a new US president
advisor?
Say, if I advise you, will you listen?
I wish more people would do that, actually.
This is another tricky one.
Vincent, you can launch a new crypto startup,
and you can choose any existing crypto CEO or entrepreneur
in the industry right now.
Who would you pick as your co-founder?
tricky one.
Sam Altman?
Sam Altman, yeah.
Interesting.
The-- so there's been a lot of things
at Token 2049 this week, the entire weekend
in the Singapore crypto week.
What is the one thing that impressed you the most,
or surprised you the most?
I mean, every conference, there's always something new.
So you know, custody was big a few years ago.
Now it's stablecoin, RWA's.
So it's not-- I mean, I'm surprised just how the community
really absorbed and rallies around the theme.
I'd say, yeah, it's been very energetic.
And to finish it off, the stablecom summit
with Vincent Chalk, the CEO of First Digital.
Vincent, if you could have lunch or dinner with one person
that are alive.
Lunch or dinner with one person that are alive,
who would you have lunch with?
I think Bill Clinton.
Bill Clinton.
What's that?
I just want to know what he did with--
[LAUGHTER]
Guys, Vincent Chalk, for us at USC, guys.
Thank you very much for inviting Vincent.
Thank you.
Here's a signed copy of the book for you as well.
Thank you very much for that.
[MUSIC PLAYING]